人人字幕组 原创翻译 双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
翻译｜Murky赤犬　薇薇安　盐湖凉白开　莱吉　辛巴　土方十琦郎
ShellyS　Lynn_宁　Pang　鱼小渊  小仓  Shishatter  八重  酥ki酱
时间轴｜柯基查　影子田园猫　富婆喵罗大　德牧袋　圣伯纳圣
校对｜酸奶还是想养金毛　后期｜8T　总监｜somehacker　小酸奶
字幕转制｜天外生物
感谢原字幕制作者
一条狗的使命
生命的意义是什么
What is the meaning of life?
我们是因为什么原因而生的吗
Are we here for a reason?
我们为什么要活着
Is there a point to any of this?
起初 我也不知道是怎么回事
First, I had no idea what was going on.
我什么都看不见
I... I couldn't see a thing.
很温暖
It was warm.
这是我的妈妈
There was my mother.
每一天 我都过得很愉快
Every day, I had fun.
过得愉快就是生命的意义吗
Was having fun the point?
全部的意义
The whole point?
不对 肯定不会这么简单的
No, it couldn't be that simple.
这有一只
Here's one.
然后一切都结束了
And then it was over.
你就这样了
That's it for you.
[捕狗队]
不能再玩闹了
No more fun.
好像这一生过得太短了
It seemed like such a short life.
我做过什么事情吗
I mean, what exactly did I do?
只是一直玩耍
There was some playing.
吃东西
There was some eating.
还在泥里打滚
I dug in the dirt.
但是当我真正思考起来之后
But when I really thought about it,
我真的没做什么事
it didn't add up to much.
我回来了
I was back.
我又变成一条小狗了
And I was a puppy again.
我还活着 准备好思考生命的大问题
Alive and ready to ask the big questions.
去刨根问底
To dig for answers.
先让我进去
Just let me in there.
我在哪呢
Where am I?
你这里还有什么狗
So what else do you have?
还有这一只
Uh, this one here.
- 这是什么品种  - 这是红毛猎犬
- What is it?  - It's a red retriever.
好狗狗
Nice dog.
不挑食 而且容易训练
Good breed. Easy to train.
你这里有没有小一点的品种
You got something smaller?
我还有几只小约克夏犬
I got some cute yorkies over here.
还有日本狆
I got this Japanese chin.
贵宾犬
Uh, poodle.
这边是柯基
Corgi over here.
还有博美
Got a pomeranian.
看看这些好东西
Look at all this great stuff.
一定是有人知道我要来
Somebody knew I was coming.
好棒呀
Oh, yeah.
你快看
Hey, look at this.
看看我们找到了什么
What do we have here?
看看这个小家伙
Look at this little guy.
肯定能值几个钱
Bet it's worth a couple bucks.
第二轮就输了
Yeah, it was a knockout in the second round.
钱都输光了 这在等着
I lost everything. Hang tight, guy.
这次该你请客了吧
Now, you're buying this time.
今天不行 伙计
Not today, buddy.
我思考着我的生活
I thought about my life.
我还有好多问题没有解决
I still had so many questions.
但是我现在只有一个问题
But I kept coming back to the same one:
我要怎么才能喝上水
How do I get a drink of water?
你想要一个冰淇淋吗
Do you want to get an ice cream?
好呀
Sure.
要什么口味的
What flavor?
妈妈 我听到里面有声音
Mom, I hear something in there.
宝贝
Hey, honey.
伊森
Ethan!
妈妈 快过来
Hey, mom, come here.
我的天哪
My god.
它看起来渴极了
It looks so thirsty.
车里面太热了
It's too hot in there.
我们要把它救出来
I think we need to get him out.
这个门打不开
I can't open the door.
等等 门被锁上了
Wait, it's locked.
求你了 妈妈
Please, mom.
后退
Okay, stand back.
你个小可怜
You poor thing.
可怜的小东西
You poor, poor thing.
你还好吗 伙计
How are you, boy?
- 没事吧  - 这是什么情况
- Good?  - What... what is this?
- 妈妈  - 一个小男孩
- Mom!  - A boy?
- 伙计  - 小男孩
- Boy...  - A boy!
- 你还好吗  - 我从来不知道
- Are you okay?  - I-I never knew there might be
- 世上还有小男孩这样的存在  - 是不是累坏了
- such a thing as a boy.  - Tired, huh?
我觉得这小家伙会撑过去的
I think this little guy is gonna make it.
- 我们能养他吗 妈妈  - 我不知道
- Can we keep him, mom?  - I don't know.
我觉得你爸爸可能不会…
I think your father might not...
我当时就决定了
I decided right then and there
我一定要养这个小男孩
I am definitely keeping this boy.
爸爸 我们能养他吗
Yeah! Dad, can we keep him?
谁来喂他
Well, who's gonna feed him?
- 我来  - 谁来给他洗澡
- I will.  - Who's gonna clean him?
这些都交给我吧 爸爸
I'll do everything, dad.
- 你觉得你已经准备好了吗  - 是的
- You think you're ready to do it?  - Yeah.
- 我不知道 儿子  - 他是个好孩子
- Oh, I don't know, son.  - He's a good boy.
是个乖宝宝
He's a good boy.
求你了
Come on, please.
它是只猎犬 爸爸
He's a retriever, dad.
他会帮你拿拖鞋的
He'll fetch your slippers.
下雨天还会帮你拿报纸
And the paper when it rains.
你让他拿什么都可以
Name something you want fetched.
他都能做到
He can do it.
看 过来
Look. Hey, come here!
你在干什么
What are you doing?
伊森和我觉得
So, Ethan and I discussed that the dog
- 他可以照顾好这条狗  - 过来 乖孩子
- would be his responsibility.  - Come here! Yeah. Good boy.
求你了 爸爸
Please, dad?
他需要朋友
Come on. He needs a pal.
听着 你和你妈妈一起说服我
All right, this thing that you two are doing,
这不公平
it's dirty pool, okay?
把他带出去
Take him away.
我要和你妈妈单独谈谈
I want to talk to your mother alone.
好的
Okay.
我们可以留它到明天
We'll keep it till tomorrow...
你紧张吗 伙计 别紧张
You nervous, boy? Don't be.
不会有事的
It'll be okay. Yeah.
我们没有多少选择
We don't have much choice.
狗很麻烦的
They make a mess.
- 你还要给它洗澡  - 拜托
- You gotta clean 'em.  - Oh, come on.
- 过不了多久他就烦了  - 别这样 吉姆
- He's gonna be bored with it.  - Oh, come on, Jim.
你知道的 你知道他三分钟热度
You know it. You know how he is.
如果他不同意的话
If he says no,
我们可以离家出走 去找新家
we can run off and go find another family.
伊森
Ethan?
什么
Yeah?
你能养狗了
You have a dog.
太棒了 太好了
Yes! Oh, my gosh, yes!
天呐 谢谢
Oh, my gosh, thank you!
快来 快来
Come on! Come on!
贝利
Bailey.
应该是宝贝的贝 锋利的利
B-a-I-l-e-y, I-I would think.
我是伊森
And I'm Ethan.
我是他的主人
I'm the owner.
他知道我名字怎么写吗
Do you think he knows how to spell my name?
应该知道 亲爱的
I would think so, honey.
那就好
Here you go.
[伊森·蒙哥马利]
好孩子
Good boy.
[贝利]
真好
Here you go.
准备好了吗
Ready?
来吧 贝利
Come on, Bailey.
贝利 坐下
Bailey, sit.
坐下
Sit.
打个滚 打个滚
Roll over. Roll over.
快把那个吐出来
Get that out of your mouth!
Get that out of your mouth.
好了 来这边
Okay. Come here.
握个手 握个手
Shake your paw. Shake your paw.
来吧 好孩子
Come on. Yeah, good boy!
转个身 转个身
Turn around. Turn around.
- 来吧  - 他在说些什么
- Come on.  - What's he saying?
- 字数太多了  - 来吧 来吧
- It's too many words.  - Come on. Okay.
- 我还是干这个吧  - 过来
- I'm gonna do this now.  - Come here.
干得好 干得好
Good job. Good job.
但相比之下 有个词重复了很多次
But one word got said more than any other.
贝利 贝利 贝利 贝利 贝利
Bailey, Bailey, Bailey, Bailey, Bailey.
过了一会儿
After a while,
我开始明白这个词的重要性
I came to understand the words that mattered.
我养了个男孩 他叫伊森
I had a boy, and his name was Ethan.
我也有名字
I got a name.
我叫贝利 贝利 贝利 贝利 贝利
My name was Bailey, Bailey, Bailey, Bailey, Bailey.
亲爱的 真希望知道你和韦斯之间…
Oh, gee, honey, I wish I'd have known that you and Wes were...
我知道了自己在家的地位
I learned my place in the pack.
妈妈喜欢我
Mom liked me.
爸爸喜欢我
Dad liked me.
- 是的 是的我知道  - 超级喜欢
- Yes. Yes, no, I understand.  - A lot.
不好意思 稍等一下
Oh, excuse me. Hold on. Come on.
一边儿去
Get down a bit.
真替猫感到悲哀
I was sad for the cat.
很明显他也想当一只狗
Obviously, he wanted to be a dog.
当不成又不是我的错
Wasn't my fault he couldn't be a dog.
伊森 该睡觉啦
Ethan, it's time to go to bed.
该关灯了好吗
Time to turn out the light, okay?
好的
Okay.
好了 来吧 来吧
Okay, come on. Come on.
来吧 来吧
Come on. Come on.
“别 别这么做 队长”
"Don't! Don't do it, cap.
“给他吧 巴基”
"Let him have it, bucky.
“我们得给他点颜色看看”
"We'll pound some sense into this character.
“砰 泰山压顶”
"Pow! Stomp!
“它冲着我们来了”
"It's coming right at us.
“快跳下去逃生”
Jump for your lives!"
伊森总能想出这样有趣的游戏
Ethan always came up with such great games.
躲在毯子下说话 真是个天才
Making noise under a blanket. Genius.
每晚睡着之后
Every night as I fell asleep,
我都会觉得养一只伊森真开心
I thought about how happy I was that I had an Ethan.
也庆幸自己不是猫
And that I wasn't a cat.
贝利 到车里来
Bailey, get in the car.
来吧 孩子
Come on, boy.
我们走
Come on!
当家人想让我出去透透气时
Whenever the family wanted me to get some fresh smells,
我们都会开车兜兜风
we all got in the car for a ride.
青草 绿树 蟾蜍 青苔 臭鼬
Grass, tree, toad, moss, skunk,
死臭鼬 池塘
dead skunk, pond,
泥土 山羊
mud, goat.
山羊
Goat!
人们每天都在思索同一个问题
Everyone was asking themself the same question
“为什么不是所有的东西都有山羊味”
"Why can't everything smell like goat?"
臭死了
Ooh, it stinks!
看看是谁来了
Oh, look who's here!
猜猜我们还带了谁
Guess what we got.
带了谁
What have you got?
你们带了谁
What'd you get?
下来吧 贝利
Come on, Bailey.
- 我的天 看看它  - 一只小狗狗
- Oh, my. Look at this.  - Oh! A puppy! -Oh, my gosh.
孩子 看这里
Here, boy. Here.
它要去哪儿
Where's he going?
我常常觉得
Sometimes I thought
生活中东想西想很浪费时间
that trying to make sense out of life could be a waste of time.
直接享受生活 顺其自然
Maybe it was better to just really enjoy life
会不会更好呢
and leave it at that.
咦 大家去哪里了
Hey, where'd everybody go?
小鸡们呢
Where's all the chickens?
贝利 贝利 贝利
Bailey! Bailey, Bailey!
伊森 伊森 伊森 伊森 伊森
Ethan, Ethan, Ethan, Ethan, Ethan!
老天爷 看看谁来啦
Oh, my goodness! Look who's here!
不知道为什么
For some reason,
他们不愿意和我一起玩这个球
they wouldn't share this ball with me.
跑吧 伊森 快跑
Yes! Run, Ethan, run!
众所周知
Everybody knows
在球类运动历史上
there's never been a game in the history of balls
还没有过狗狗参赛的先例
that can't be improved by having a dog in it.
但这个球长得有点奇怪
But there was something weird about this ball.
宝藏
Treasure.
这才叫生活
Ah, this is the life.
谁还要吗 吉姆 你的咖啡
Anyone else? Jim, your coffee?
- 谢谢  - 给你
- Oh, thank you.  - Here you go.
大家都到齐了
Here we all are.
对呀 好好吃吧
Yeah. Enjoy your meal.
我喜欢老年人
I liked the old humans.
他们懂我
They got me.
可以不要喂狗吃东西了吗
Would you please stop feeding the dog?
我们在试着训练它
We're trying to train him.
我告诉过你了
I told you.
被抓现行了 不好意思
You caught me. I'm sorry.
可以把果酱递给我吗
Could you pass me the jam, please?
当我注意力不在吃上时 我就会乱想
When I wasn't thinking about food, my mind wandered.
我为什么会在这里
Why am I here?
有什么目的吗
What's the purpose?
真爽 接着揉
Oh, yeah. Keep rubbing.
会有更多的培根吗
And... Might there be more bacon?
看他的盘子里
Oh, look at his plate.
要知道 照这么吃下去
You know, the way you eat,
等你长大了之后 我们几个加起来
you're gonna grow up to be bigger
都不够你的块头大
than all of us put together.
前提是得有个和平年代
If there's a world to grow up in.
俄国人在古巴布置了导弹
These Russians are putting missiles in Cuba.
我们非得现在说这个吗
Do we have to talk about that now?
- 没有啊  - 对了 吉姆
- No.  - So, um, Jim,
听说你换了份办公室工作
I hear you're up for a new office job.
不如跟我们讲讲这个吧
Why don't you tell us about that?
并没有谈成
That didn't work out.
他们想让他出外勤
Well, they want him in the field.
顶级销售员年年都有他名字
He's one of the top sellers every year.
我干的活是个烫手山芋
I got the job nobody wants.
吉姆 你非要这样吗
Jim, do you have to?
核打击已经近在咫尺了
We're three seconds away from nuclear annihilation.
我和贝利能离桌了吗
Uh, can me and Bailey be excused?
当然
Sure.
伊森很难过
Ethan was sad.
我不知道为什么
I didn't know why.
嗨 贝利
Hey, Bailey.
还记得美国队长吗
Captain America, remember?
他可以一瞬间就拆掉炸弹
He could take out that bomb in a second.
啪
Pow!
咻
Zap!
看来你挺喜欢呀
Oh, you like it, don't you?
来呀 来呀
Come on. Come on.
就是这样
Yeah, boy.
贝利 准备好了
Okay, Bailey.
去捡回来
Get it, boy!
加油呀
Come on!
就是这样伙计
Yeah, boy! Come on.
来 去哪儿了
Come on. Oh, where'd it go?
去哪儿了
Where'd it go?
在这呢 你看那是什么
Come on, boy! Oh! What is that?
把它捡回来
Get it, boy!
加油 加油 拿到它
Oh, come on. Come on, get it!
- 我们玩了一下午球  - 就是这样
- We played with that ball all afternoon.  - Yeah! Come on!
- 伊森特别喜欢这个游戏  - 干得漂亮
- Ethan loved it.  - Good boy!
捡回来
Get it!
加油 加油
Come on! Come on.
爸 瞧瞧这招
Hey, dad, watch this.
看看他的能耐
Look what he can do.
贝利 准备好了吗
Okay, Bailey. Ready?
准备好了
Ready.
别动
Stay. Okay.
然后
And...
就是现在
Okay.
上啊贝利
Go, Bailey!
太棒了 松开
Yeah! Out.
真厉害
That's great, pal.
谢了 老爸
Thanks, dad.
来呀来呀
Hey, hey, come on.
对的 对的
Oh, yes. Yes.
来呀 来呀
Come on. Come on.
- 祝你今天愉快  - 当天气转凉时
- You have a great day.  - When it got colder outside,
- 我们回家了  - 再见
- we all went back home.  - See ya.
- 他不会有事的 再见  - 再见
- He'll be fine. Bye.  - Bye.
每天早上 一个有轮子的大黄箱子
Every morning, a big yellow box with wheels
都会把伊森从我身边带走
took Ethan away from me.
当妈妈也离开后
When mom left the house, too,
我就很孤单
I was lonely,
也会感到饿
and hungry,
而且很无聊
and bored.
幸好他们把猫留下了
At least they left the cat.
我会来教他一些狗的知识
I'd give him his dog lessons.
要学的还很多呢
So much to learn.
狗才不会躲在枕头下面
No, dogs do not hide under pillows.
过来
Come on. Come...
过来 闻闻我
Come on, sniff me.
闻闻我
Sniff me!
你什么都不知道
You don't know anything.
你总是在清嗓子
You clear your throat a lot.
贝利 不
Oh, Bailey, no.
老爸
Hi, dad.
伊丽莎白
Elizabeth?
- 这 这  - 伊丽莎白
- This... this...  - Elizabeth!
你在吗
Hello?
那是我的拖鞋
That's my slipper.
贝利 贝利
Bailey! Bailey!
快回来
Come... get back here.
别这样 贝利
Bailey, no!
快过来 贝利
Bailey, come here.
过来 过来
Come here.Come here.
贝利 过来
Bailey, come here.
- 把它给我  - 当老爸心情好时
- Give me that.  - When dad was in the right mood,
和他一起玩很开心
he was so much fun to play with.
别这样 松口 松口 松口
Come on, let go. Let go. Let go.
贝利 那不是你的
That's not yours, Bailey.
那是我的 那是我的
That's mine. That's mine!
你给我过来 过来
You come over here. Come on!
伊森 我领导今晚要来
Ethan, my boss is coming over tonight,
不能让他看到我的办公室乱成这样
and he cannot see my office like this.
你明白了吗
Do you understand?
你得告诉这只狗谁才是老大
You have got to start telling this dog who's boss.
牵着他 快牵着他
Here, take him. Just take him.
然后你说 我才是老大
And you say, "I am the boss!"
你得向他证明谁才是老大
You gotta show him who's boss.
好了 把东西都收拾好
All right, everything goes back where it belongs.
我要这里干干净净的
I want this place spick-and-span.
你明白吗
Do you understand?
你明白了吗
Well, do you understand?
Do you understand?!
- 明白了  - 很好
- Yes, sir.  - Thank you.
我只想让事情向我喜欢的那样发展
I want everything just the way I like it.
干干净净
Spick-and-span.
为什么 因为我才是老大 这就是为什么
Why? Because I'm the boss. That's why.
我是老大 你是狗老大
I'm the boss man, and you're the boss dog.
狗老大
Boss dog.
伊森
Ethan.
快来 我们准备吧
Come on. Let's go.
客人马上就回来了
We got guests coming any minute.
麻利点
Chop-chop.
- 吉姆  - 怎么了
- Jim?   - What?
你能帮我下吗
Jim, can you help me?
- 怎么了  - 我不知道怎么调新加坡司令
- Huh?  - I don't know how to make a Singapore sling.
什么
What?
我来教你
Oh, I'll show you.
我可以调威士忌冷饮
I can make a whiskey cobbler.
等下 秘方在这
Wait, here's the recipe.
伊丽莎白 你在 你在干什么
Elizabeth, what are you... What are you doing?
我们需要烈酒
Well, we need spirit...
一九〇七年圣高登斯金鹰硬币
Saint-gaudens 1907 golden eagle.
是真金
Real gold.
不要啊
No!
伊森对我很好
Ethan was good to me.
- 别吞下去啊  - 他总是分享他的食物
- Boy! No!  - He always shared his food.
还在你嘴里吗 你吞下去了吗
Do you have it in your mouth? Did you swallow it?
- 虽然不是我最喜欢吃的  - 快给我
- Wasn't my favorite treat.  - Come on, show me.
- 他想要回来  - 快给我
- And he wanted it back.  - Come on, come on.
为什么
Why?
- 我们准时到了  - 你好 爱伦
- We made it.  - Hello! Ellen.
请进 欢迎光临
Come in. Welcome.
我很高兴我们终于能来这里
I am glad we were finally able to make it out here,
我一直
because I have been wanting to,
想看看外勤办公室
visit the field office for a while now.
这里真不错
Oh, yes, and it's... It's so nice and...
郊区很安静
Quiet out here in the suburbs.
- 是的  - 是的
- It sure is. Yeah.  - Yes.
我们非常开心你们能过来
Well, we're happy to have you.
我是想说我们
Um, so I-I've been meaning to say we...
对你过去一年业绩的印象很深刻
Uh, we're real impressed with your numbers this past year, Jim.
你做的非常好
Real impressed.
我很高兴你提到这个
You know, I'm glad you brought that up.
我正好也想和你谈一下这件事
Uh, I've actually been meaning to talk to you about that.
我觉得既然业绩这么好
You know, I-I was thinking, with the numbers so high,
也许是时候让我不再出差
maybe it's time I get off the road
转而去坐办公室了
and take an office position.
我们需要你继续出差
Well, we... we really need you on the road.
你是整个业务的骨干精英
That's the backbone of the whole operation really.
吉姆 说实话
I'll be honest, Jim.
你是最优秀的旅行推销员
You are one of our best traveling salesmen.
我意思是 我疯了才会让你坐办公室
I mean, I would be crazy to take you out of the field.
你还在收集硬币吗
Um, are you still collecting coins?
当然
Oh, sure.
有精品吗
What... what's your showpiece?
一九〇七年的圣高登斯金鹰硬币
1907 Saint-gaudens golden eagle.
赫尔曼 虽然我不懂硬币
Well, Herman, i don't know anything about coins,
但我知道金鹰硬币是很特别的
but I know that that is special.
- 那是很特别  - 那可是珍品
- That is special.  - That is a treasure.
是啊 我还从没亲眼见过呢
Yeah, I have never seen one up close before.
- 它可不是一般的硬币  - 是的 它还特别漂亮
- It's quite a coin.  - Yeah, it's a beauty.
我去拿给你看
I'll show you. I'll go get it.
吃完饭再去吧
Well, maybe after dinner.
那我一会去拿
Let me go get it later.
我可以去玩吗
May I please be excused?
什么
Huh?
我可以去玩吗
May I please be excused?
我想带贝利出去玩
Need to take Bailey out for a walk.
当然了 宝贝
Sure, honey.
拉出来 快
Go on, do it.
求你了 贝利
Please, Bailey.
求你了 贝利 拉出来 快
Please, Bailey, do it. Come on.
他想让我干什么
What does he want from me?
快拉 快拉
Come on. Come on.
我真想知道他在说什么
I really wish I knew what he was saying.
拉啊 拉啊 快
Go! Go! Come on!
你怎么回事 快拉啊
What's your problem? Come on!
我不知道他为什么不开心 但这让我很着急
I don't know why he was so upset, but it made me anxious.
而我着急的时候 肠胃蠕动就非常快
And when I'm anxious, things kind of move super fast.
这还是第一次
This was a first.
从来没见过他这么高兴地清理我的粪便
I'd never seen him so happy to clean up after me.
太棒了 找到了
Yes! Found it!
这个甜点的关键是不能做得太甜了
It's important it shouldn't be too sweet.
- 不 很好吃  - 看到了吗
- No, it's nice. Mmm.  - See this?
接下来
Now, this...
你们将
That's something
- 迎来一场视觉的盛宴  - 不
- for your eyes to feast on.  - No!
怎么了
What?
有老鼠
There's a rat.
- 什么 什么  - 就在那
- What? What?  - Right there!
- 在哪 不 我讨厌老鼠  - 在哪
- Where? No, I don't like rats.  - Where?
- 在哪  - 没事
- Where is it?  - It's okay.
桌子下面
Under the table.
- 我爱老鼠  - 对 捉住它 贝利
- I love rats.  - Yeah, go get it, Bailey.
- 我什么也没有看见  - 在哪
- I don't see anything.  - Where?
- 跑到那了  - 等等
- It's running over there.  - Whoa, whoa, whoa, wait!
抓住狗 抓住狗
Get that dog! Get the dog.
- 抓住狗  - 贝利
- Get the dog. Get the...  - Bailey!
- 我什么都没看到  - 给我过来
- I don't see anything.  - Come here.
- 就在那里  - 也许你看到的是小灰
- It's right there.  - Maybe you saw Smokey.
- 绝对不是小灰  - 不 不是小灰
- Definitely not Smokey.  - No, it wasn't Smokey.
我真的怕老鼠 我讨厌老鼠
I really don't like rats. I don't like rats.
比起你怕它们 是老鼠更怕你吧
It's more scared of you than you are of him.
给我过来 贝利
Come here. Come here, Bailey.
- 过来  - 你能抓到他吗 抓住他
- Come here! Come here.  - Can you grab him? Grab him.
- 吉姆  - 贝利 过来
- Jim.  - Bailey! Bailey, come here!
过来
Come here!
停下 别跑 贝利
Wait. Please, Bailey.
- 你能抓到他吗 吉姆  - 我什么都没看到
- Can you grab him, Jim?  - I don't see anything.
贝利
Bailey!
贝利 过来
Bailey, come here.
我觉得老鼠已经跑了
I think it's gone now.
我好讨厌老鼠
Oh, I don't like rats!
贝利
Bailey!
什么情况
What was that?
赫尔曼
Herman!
贝利 过来
Bailey, come here!
快来 快点
Come here! Come on!
你抓到他了吗 吉姆 抓到没
You got him, Jim? You got him?
升职什么的再也不用想了
Any chances I had of a promotion, forget it.
爸爸 别这样
Dad! Dad, stop!
- 这不是它的错  - 你让我们跟傻子一样
- It's not his fault. It's...  - You made us look like fools!
爸爸散发这个味道的时候说话总是很大声
Dad always talked so loud when he smelled this way.
别惩罚他 都是我的错
Don't punish him! My fault!
吉姆 你要不要先冷静一下
Jim, why don't we take a moment before you...
不必了 从现在起 狗待在这里
No, from now on, he stays out here.
它什么也没做
He didn't do anything!
我不想看到他
I do not want to see him.
别让我在屋子里再见到他
I do not want to see him in the house.
可是外面冷
But it's cold outside.
他有毛的
Well, he's got fur for that.
我们至少得给他铺个毯子吧
We should at least set out a blanket.
它只是条狗
It's a dog!
伊森
Ethan?
狗狗 你还好吗
Hey, boy. Good?
真抱歉
I'm so sorry.
都是我的错
It's all my fault.
尽管我看不到他
Even though I couldn't see him,
我知道伊森那晚很难过
I knew Ethan was very sad that night.
乖狗狗
Hey, boy.
外面太冷了 是吧
It's cold out there, isn't it?
我知道他需要我
I knew he needed me.
我也需要他
And I needed him, too.
真是条乖狗狗
You're a good boy.
准备好了吗
Ready, boy?
好 过来
Okay. Come here.
来
Come here.
快来 贝利
Come on, Bailey.
好的 准备好了吗
Okay, boy. Ready?
三 二
Three, two...
一
One!
快来
Come on!
完美
Yeah, boy.
- 别这样  - 我们再来一次
- Oh, come on.  - Let's do it again.
- 太棒了  - 好
- Yes!  - Yeah!
好球 伊森 传得漂亮
Nice throw, Ethan. Nice throw.
打得好
Nice play.
伊森 传得漂亮
Great pass, Ethan.
真厉害 棒极了
Got 'em now. Right on.
你 你每次都把球传到他那个位置
You-you get it to him every time.
确实
Yeah, exactly.
因为每次我们用那种战术的时候
'Cause every time we run that play...
所有人都想走在老大旁边
Everybody wanted to walk next to the Alpha male.
是啊 我就是这个意思
Yeah, that's what I mean.
几乎所有人
Almost everybody.
- 因为每次他都正好在那个位置  - 是的
- 'Cause he's right there every single time.  - Yep.
- 伊森 为什么你总是带着这条狗  - 什么
- Ethan, why do you always have this dog with you?  - Hmm?
是用来替代女朋友的还是干吗的
What? It's like a girlfriend replacement or something?
说得好 托德
Yeah, good one, Todd.
亲一个
Give a little kiss? Huh?
我只是问问
I'm just asking.
不好意思
Excuse me.
我很抱歉 托德
Oh, I'm sorry, Todd.
刚才 是不是我的替补女朋友绊倒了你
Did my, uh, girlfriend replacement just trip you?
很好笑
Very funny.
放轻松 伙计 我就是开个玩笑
Relax, man. I'm kidding.
那只狗都在笑你
The dog's laughing at you.
- 狗不会笑 你个白痴  - 贝利 过来
- Dogs don't laugh, you moron.  - Bailey, come here.
好好笑
That's funny.
- 都拿好了吗  - 拿好了
- Got everything?  - Yeah.
一开始卢传那脚球的时候
When Lou dropped that pass at the start,
- 我还以为我们死定了  - 我就知道
- I thought we were done, man.  - I know!
来
Here.
贝利 过来
Bailey, come here.
爸爸
Hey, dad.
- 你饿了吗  - 饿死了
- You hungry?  - I'm starving.
- 微波炉里有一盆砂锅菜  - 这样吗
- I got a casserole in the oven.  - Yeah?
非洲是成千上万动物的家
Africa is home to hundreds of thousands of animals.
有些看起来很滑稽
Some look comical,
有些 有些让人望而生畏
some... Some forbidding,
还有些使人着迷到
and some so entrancing that we'd like
让人想伸开手 触碰它们
to reach out and touch them...
教练今天让我打四分卫了
So, uh, coach made me starting quarterback today.
孩子 真不错
That's great, kid.
爸爸 你下次一定要来看我的比赛
You gotta come to my next game, dad.
我是认真的 我现在打得更好了
I'm serious. I'm better now.
你已经很久没来看过了
It's been a long time.
好
Okay.
爸爸真可怜
Poor dad.
这地方太棒了
This place is great.
这儿有这么多好闻的
Oh, there's so much to smell here.
还有好吃的
and eat.
到处都是
Oh, it's everywhere.
喂我 喂我
Feed me. Feed me.
你也想玩这个吗
You want to go next?
伊森身上的味道突然不一样了
Ethan had a different smell all of a sudden.
一股汗味
A sweaty smell.
有人想坐那个过山车吗
Who wants to go on that roller coaster?
不知道这跟那个女孩儿有没有关系
Hmm. I wonder if that girl had anything to do with it.
贝利贝利贝利贝利
Oh! Hey, hey, hey! Bailey, Bailey, Bailey, Bailey!
抱歉
Sorry.
抱歉 抱歉
Sorry. Sorry.
刚刚是那只狗 不是我
That was the dog. That wasn't me.
我不会做那种事的
I wouldn't do that.
或许
Okay, well, maybe
你该教狗懂点礼貌
you should teach your dog some manners.
我在努力 他 他不是太聪明
I've been trying. He's, uh... he's not too smart.
是吗
Really?
你听到他刚刚说你什么了吗
Wow. Did you hear what he said about you?
我看你长得挺聪明的
You look pretty smart to me.
是啊
Oh, yeah.
这么机灵的眼睛
Such intelligent eyes.
我屁股有点痒
My butt itches.
帅哥 你叫什么
What's your name, handsome?
他叫 他叫贝利
He's, uh... he's Bailey.
- 贝利  - 贝利
- Bailey, yeah.  - Bailey.
贝利 你看起来是只特别棒的狗狗
Now, you seem like a very good dog, Bailey.
- 是的  - 抱歉
- Yeah.  - Excuse me?
- 玩得不错  - 谢谢你
- Nice job.  - Oh. Thank you.
真好
Nice.
别让他够着那个
Hey, hey, hey, hey. Keep that away from him.
- 好好好  - 你真的很擅长这个
- Okay, okay, okay.  - You're really good at that.
谢谢
Thanks.
- 确实很好  - 真的吗
- Like, really good.  - Yeah?
我刚刚在那边看你来着
I was watching you over there.
不是那样的
Not like that.
我是说
I mean... yeah.
再见
See ya.
如果我们以后不会再见面的话
Hey, uh, if we never speak again,
我想收回我之前的那句话
I just want to take back what I said before
我刚刚说我的狗不聪明
about my dog not being smart.
但他其实很聪明
He's actually really smart.
绝对比我聪明
Definitely smarter than me.
现在他们俩身上都有那种汗味了
Now they both had a sweaty smell.
你想去 你想去买个热狗之类的吗
You want to, uh... you want to get a hot dog or something?
爆米花呢
Popcorn?
好啊
Sure.
走吧
Okay, let's do it.
这边儿有些卖得不错的
There's some good ones over here.
贝利 过来
Hey, Bailey, come here.
我想去救他们 但我不知道怎么救
I wanted to save them, but I didn't know how.
- 来吧  - 不玩了吗
- Come on.  - We done?
- 刚刚玩得很开心  - 下次不玩了
- Oh, that was good.  - Never again.
不 很好玩啊
No! It was fun!
谢谢你呀
Thank you.
伊森有麻烦了
Uh-oh, Ethan's in trouble.
我要死了
I'm gonna die.
我要死了 我要死了
I'm gonna die. I'm gonna die.
- 你怎么搞的  - 别担心 伊森
- What's wrong with you?  - Oh, don't worry, Ethan.
- 我会帮你的  - 别别别别别
- I'll help.  - Hey, hey, hey, hey, no, no, no, no, no.
待着别动 待着别动
Stay back. Stay back.
- 贝利 别别别  - 但我在帮你啊
- Bailey, no, no, no.  - But I'm helping.
贝利 停下 贝利贝利贝利贝利贝利
Bailey, stop! Bailey, Bailey, Bailey, Bailey, Bailey,
贝利 停下停下停下停下
Bailey, stop, stop, stop, stop. Hey. No.
谢谢你 谢谢你们俩送我回来
Thank you. Thank you both for the ride.
我刚刚为什么要吃这么多热狗
Why did I eat so many meat logs?
我们应该一起做些什么
Yeah, we should do something.
会很不错的
Yes, that would be nice.
今天玩得很开心
It was fun.
是的
It was.
除了要买下二十八个热狗 都很好
Except for having to pay for 28 hot dogs.
不好意思
excuse me.
- 你最好快点走了 快点走吧  - 好吧
- Yeah, you better go. You better go quick.  - Okay.
- 拜拜  - 拜拜
- Okay. Bye.  - See ya.
从那时起
From that moment on,
这个女孩儿就成了我们的一员
the girl was a member of our pack.
我喜欢她
I liked her.
而且她闻起来像饼干的味道
Plus she smelled like biscuits.
去 去 贝利
Go! Go, Bailey!
我们每天都在一起
We spent every day together.
- 真是好孩子  - 准备好了吗贝利
- That a boy.  - Ready, Bailey?
- 好了 扔 扔  - 好了 扔了
- Yeah. Go, go, go.  - Ready? Okay, here we go.
- 真棒  - 跳的真好
- Oh! Good boy!  - What a dive.
那是什么
What was that?
- 真棒  - 游啊
- Oh! Good boy!  - Swim!
拿回来
Bring it back!
真棒
That a boy.
- 快过来  - 真棒 真棒
- Come here, boy.  - That a boy. That a boy.
- 来  - 真棒
- Come on.  - Oh, good boy!
- 真棒 真棒  - 是啊 真棒
- Good boy. Good boy.  - Yeah, good boy.
小心头
Watch your head.
真棒
Good boy.
- 不 这不可以  - 不
- No, it's not okay.  - No.
反正我也要走了
Besides, I'm going.
- 为什么  - 因为你从不听我说话
- Why?   - You don't listen!
每次我问你那些东西去哪了的时候…
Every time I ask you where something comes from...
你告诉我 你告诉我那些东西去哪了
You tell me! You tell me where it's going!
因为是我挣来的 我挣来的 我挣来的
Cause I earn it! I earn it! I earn it!
要不我们去城里吧
You, uh... you want to go to town instead?
好的
Yeah.
- 贝利  - 走吧 贝利
- Bailey.  - Come on, Bailey!
我们一起嚎叫
We howled together.
有时候我们就坐在车里
And sometimes we would sit in the car
哪里都不去
not even going anywhere.
伊森和汉娜会缠在一起舔对方
Ethan and Hannah would wrestle and lick each other.
他们是在抢食物吗
Are they fighting over food?
也许汉娜在她嘴里藏了点什么
Maybe Hannah's hiding something in her mouth.
没 什么也没有
Nope. Nothing in there.
我的天… 你是怎么了
Oh, my... What's going on with you?
它喜欢你
Man, he loves you.
但是不管他
But no matter how much
多努力在那里找食物 他从没找到过什么
he looked for food in there, he never found anything.
而且他
And he looked.
找了很多遍
A lot.
你能感觉的到
You can feel it.
夏天要结束了
Summer's ending.
是最好的夏天了
Best summer ever.
是的
Yeah.
我不想回学校
I don't want to go back to school.
你想的
Yes, you do.
我想
I do?
是的
Yes.
你会在一个好学校
You are gonna get a big football scholarship
得到一大笔橄榄球奖学金
at a good school.
我会申请那个学校
And then I'm gonna apply to that school
然后得到一笔学术奖学金
and get an academic scholarship.
我们都会上大学
And then we'll both be at college,
然后永远不会分开
and we'll never be apart.
你把一切都计划好了啊
You've got it all planned out, huh?
的确是的
Yes, indeed.
这是个好计划
That's a good plan.
对吧 贝利
Right, Bailey?
什么 你说了什么
What? What did you say?
- 拜拜  - 拜
- See ya.  - Bye.
拜
Bye!
明天见
See you tomorrow.
真乖
Good boy.
我得走了
I gotta go.
你要去哪
Where are you going?
我要去喝点啤酒
I'm getting some beer.
我只是想让你声音放小一点
All I ask is for you to lower your voice.
- 我就这点…  - 别说了 别说了
- That's all I...  - Stop, stop. Just stop!
你能小声一点吗
Will you please just keep it down?
我的父母就在楼下 吉姆 你别闹了
My parents are upstairs, Jim. You need to stop.
好吧 对不起 你是对的
Oh, I'm sorry. You know, you're right.
好吧 那我就不闹了
Fine. I will stop doing it, then.
我走行吧 我就直接走
I'll just go! I'll just leave.
你觉得这样好吗
Does that sound good to you?
- 出来吧  - 你觉得这样好吗
- Come on, boy.  - Does it sound good to you?
- 我不知道 你说呢  - 你觉得
- Well, I don't know. You tell me.  - Will that be
这样好吗 我就这样走了你高兴吗
good for you? Will you be happy then if I just...?
不 告诉我 告诉我你高不高兴
No, just tell me. Just tell me if you'll be happy.
- 别说了 走吧  - 我会走的
- Stop it. Just go!  - Oh, I'm gonna go!
好吧 我走
Fine, I'll go.
你能不能进屋来…
Will you just come back inside...
别说了伊丽莎白 闭嘴 闭嘴
Stop it, Eliz... Shut up! Shut up!
进屋来吧 我是在帮你 吉姆
Just come back inside. I am trying to help you, Jim.
你是在帮我 你想帮我
You're trying to help me? You want to help me?
你是我妻子 伊丽莎白
You're my wife, Elizabeth.
- 你应该支持我  - 我是在支持你
- You should support me.  - I do support you.
- 你能不能进屋来…  - 小伙子
- Will you just come back inside...  - Hey. Hey, pal.
你在监视我吗
You spying on me?
什么
What?
你在监视我吗
You spying on me?
- 别吼他 吉姆  - 过来
- Leave him alone, Jim.  - Come here.
- 别吼他  - 你有什么想说的吗
- Leave him alone.  - No. You got something to say?
- 我刚到家  - 过来
- I just got home.  - Come here.
- 看看他是怎么看着我的  - 不
- Look at how he looks at me.  - No.
- 我真讨厌他这样看着我  - 没事的 伊森
- I am so sick of the way you look at me.  - It's okay, Ethan.
- 没关系  - 放松 放松
- It's okay.  - Just relax. Relax.
- 看看他是怎么看着我的  - 你在干什么
- Look at how you look at me.  - What are you doing?
- 这跟他没关系  - 你别管
- This has nothing to do with him.  - Stay out of it.
- 这跟他没…  - 你别管
- This has nothing...  - You stay out of it!
你在干什么
What are you doing?
冷静 冷静一下 冷静一下
Easy. Take it easy. Take it easy.
- 你是对的  - 我的天…
- You're right.  - God...
你是对的
You're right.
我要…
I'm gonna...
你别想再碰她一下
Don't you ever touch her again!
你听见了没
You hear me?
你得走了
You gotta go.
妈妈 他得走了
Mom, he's gotta go.
他不能待在这了
He can't stay here.
妈妈 你没事吧
Mom, you okay?
没事 对不起
Yeah. I'm sorry.
你确定你什么都带着了吗
Sure you got everything?
让他跟我说句话
Just let her talk to me.
- 上车吧 爸爸  - 我搞得定
- Just get in the car, dad.  - I got it.
从那时起
From that moment on,
伊森变成我们的头了
Ethan was the leader of our pack.
当我们回家后 情况和之前不一样了
When we went home, things were different.
爸爸走了
Dad was gone.
那只猫躲了我好久
That cat had been hiding from me for a while.
现在我找到他了
And now I got it.
我找到他了
I found him!
好吧 对不起
Okay, sorry.
天哪
Geez!
上啊 红八〇 红八〇
Go! Red 80. Red 80.
- 加油 伊森  - 触底 准备 一次进攻
- Let's go, Ethan!  - Down, set, hut!
- 就是这样  - 在上面
- That's it.  - Over the top.
防守的好
Good block.
猛虎队夺得首攻
First down, tigers.
外接手接到传球
Pass caught by wide receiver...
好样的 伊森
Way to go, Ethan!
猛虎队领先十分
First and ten for the tigers.
加油 猛虎队
Come on, tigers!
准备 就位 开始
Down, set, hut!
加油 加油
Yeah! Yeah!
猛虎队触地得分
Touchdown, tigers!
真是太精彩了
That was amazing.
妈妈
Mom.
天呐
No.
全额奖学金 四年
Full scholarship. Four years.
我的天呐 真的吗
Oh, my gosh! Really?
好了 好了 行啦
Okay, okay. Come on.
- 真的吗  - 嗯
- Really? Oh!  - Yeah.
- 在这里等着好吗 狗老大  - 好
- Okay, you wait here. Okay, boss dog?  - Okay.
等着 我去给你弄些吃的 好吗
You wait here. I'll get you something to eat, okay?
知道啦
I just said okay.
乖狗狗
Good boy.
来吧 宝贝儿 烧起来
Come on, baby! Let it burn!
烧 烧 烧 好耶
Go, go, go, go, go! Yes!
- 好…  - 怎么回事
- Ye...  - What?
哈 跳梁小丑
Ah, some jokers.
- 干得好  - 打得真棒
- Good job.  - Great game, great game.
- 我来放哨  - 伊森
- I'm keeping watch.  - Hey, Ethan!
- 一切安全  - 你还好吗
- All clear.  - How you doing?
有情况
What?
他怎么来了
What was he doing here?
而且和往常一样 心情很差
And in one of his bad moods, too.
我闻得出来
I could smell it.
走啦 快点
Come on, let's go.
- 快点  - 遗传了他妈妈的智商
- Come on.  - Got his brains from his mom, huh?
是啊 但我还是没拿到奖学金
Yeah, I didn't get a scholarship, though.
爸爸
Hey, dad.
儿子
Hey, pal.
你怎么… 你怎么在这儿
What are you, uh... What are you doing here?
我看到了… 我今晚看到你了 伊森
Oh. Well, I saw you... I saw you tonight, Ethan.
- 你打得很棒  - 你看了比赛
- You did good.  - You were at the game?
是啊
Yeah.
投球投得不错
You got a good arm.
顺利被录取了吧
So everything's going good, huh?
- 这小子厉害吧  - 爸爸
- This guy, huh?  - Dad.
- 比赛打得真不错  - 爸爸
- Good game, huh?  - Dad, hey.
- 赢了比赛都很激动吧  - 爸爸
- We're all excited for the big win, huh?  - Dad.
都为这小子欢呼吧
Let's cheer for this guy!
你能不能别这样 爸爸
You don't have to do this right now, dad.
来吧 来吧
Come on! Come on, huh?
别这样好吗
Would you stop this?
好吧
Hey. All right.
好了 走吧
Come on, let's go.
给你汉堡
Want your burger?
是贝利的
For Bailey?
狗老大 真乖
Hey, boss dog. Good boy.
原来伊森的世界也并非十全十美啊
So it's not all perfect in Ethan land, huh?
难怪你要逃到密歇根去了
Now I know why you're going to Michigan, man.
想离你的酒鬼老爸远点儿吗
Get away from that alchy father of yours.
- 你最好闭嘴 托德  - 是吗
- You should shut up, Todd.  - Oh, yeah?
你 你不想让所有人都知道
You-you don't want everyone here knowing
你老爸是个酒鬼吗
that your father's a drunk?
伊森 我还得赶公交 走吧
Ethan, I have to catch my bus. Please.
显然大家都知道了
It's pretty obvious.
- 我们走吧  - 好 一会儿就走
- Can we go?  - Yeah, we're going soon.
他女朋友也开始心疼他了
Oh, oh, and his girlfriend's fighting his battles, too.
如果密歇根州大知道这样的你…
If Michigan state knew the real Ethan...
天呐
Whoa!
我说过让你闭嘴 托德
I told you to shut up, Todd.
我不喜欢这个味道
I don't like that smell.
我们上车吧
Please get in the car.
贝利 快点
Bailey, come on!
贝利 快过来 上车
Bailey, let's go. Get in the car.
什么声音
What was that?
是松鼠吗
Could that be that squirrel?
完美
Perfect.
托德闯进了我们的地盘
Todd was on our territory.
我真想咬他
Oh, I wanted to bite him.
但是伊森不让我咬人
But I remembered Ethan telling me no biting.
不管了
Then I forgot.
停下 停下 别咬
No, no, no, no, no!
伊森
Ethan.
贝利
Bailey.
贝利 别吵
Bailey, shut up.
妈妈
Mom!
妈妈 妈妈
Mom, mom, mom!
快起来 醒醒
Get up, get up, get up.
快点 快点 起来
Quick, quick. Come on, quick!
- 我们得出去  - 不行 出不去了
- We gotta get out.  - We can't. We can't.
这里 从窗户走
Come. The window.
- 快过来  - 天呐
- Come here.  - Oh, god.
着火了 着火了
Fire! Fire!
- 跳下去  - 不行 太高了
- You gotta jump.  - It's too high.
快把你的床单也拿来
Get your sheets! Get your sheets!
- 给你  - 把床单绑起来
- Here. Here.  - I just want to tie these together.
附近有梯子吗
Anyone have a ladder handy?
我们得把他们弄下来
We gotta help 'em down!
- 天呐  - 这是唯一一条生路了
- Oh, god.  - It's the only way, okay?
- 里面有多少人  - 对 就这样
- How many people are in the house?  - Okay.
快去检查一下房子后面
Check the back of the house.
快搭把手
Somebody give me a hand!
- 快 快 小心  - 接住你了
- Go, go, go.  - We got you.
好了 接住了 接到她了
Okay, we got you. Got her.
- 接到你了  - 好了
- We got you. We got you.  - Okay.
乖狗狗 乖狗狗
Good boy. Good boy.
我去后边检查
I'll check around back!
我就在你后边
I'm here-- right behind you.
好了
Okay.
不
No!
天呐
Oh!
- 快点  - 我能帮什么忙吗
- Come on.  - Is there anything I can do?
我们得帮他下来
We gotta help him down.
小心 伊森
Come on, Ethan.
你得跳下来 孩子
You need to jump, son.
伊森 快跳
Ethan, jump!
伊森
Ethan!
- 你能动吗  - 我的腿
- Okay, can you move?  - My leg!
- 好了 坚持住  - 一 二 三
- All right, come on.  - One, two, three.
小心腿
His leg.
腿好疼
My leg.
- 你会没事的  - 没事的 放心吧
- You're gonna be all right.  - It's okay. You're okay.
没事了
It's okay.
谁来牵走这条狗
Somebody hold this dog.
贝利 贝利 你不能去
Hey, Bailey. Bailey, no.
不行
No.
跟着他 和他待一起
Go with him. Go with him.
别动
No.
一 二 三
One, two, three.
会没事的 乖狗狗 他会回来的
It's going to be okay, boy. He'll be back.
安静
Easy.
不要
No. Hey, hey.
- 不要 停下  - 有只狗
- Don't! Stop!  - There's the dog.
来人抓住那条狗
Somebody get the dog.
你跑什么呢 孩子
What you running from, son?
我发誓 这是场意外 我
I swear, it... It was an accident. I...
不如你告诉我们发生了什么
Why don't you tell us what happened?
我有一支烟花
I-I-I had a firework...
你得跟我们走一趟
I think you should come with us.
但是不要 拜托 拜托
But don't... Please... please just...
这是场意外
It was an accident.
弗兰 弗兰 过来 过来
Fran! Fran, come on, come on, come on.
- 是他们到了吗  - 他们到了 是他们
- They're here?  - They're here, they're here.
- 好  - 小心点 亲爱的
- Okay.  - Be careful, dear.
我有小心
I'm... I'm being careful.
有小心
I'm being careful.
亲爱的
Hey, sweetie.
见到你真好
Good to see you.
看看你
Oh, look at you.
来 来 让我
Here, here, let...
- 我能行  - 弗兰 弗兰 弗兰
- I-I got it.  - Fran, Fran, Fran, Fran.
别这样 别
Stop it. Stop.
见到你真好 伊森
Good to see you, Ethan.
你也是
Yeah. You, too.
我一整天都在烤东西
I've been baking all day.
你的房间都整理妥当了 伊森
Got your room all set up for you, Ethan.
你们来住这里真好
It's so good to have you here.
伊森再也不想玩了
Ethan never wanted to play anymore.
贝利
Oh, Bailey.
抱歉
I'm so sorry.
尽管他走到哪儿
Even though he carried
都带着那根漂亮的新棍子
a great new stick everywhere he went.
贝利 不要
Bailey, come on. Hey!
- 不不不 贝利  - 贝利
- No, no, no, no, no, Bailey.  - Bailey.
别咬 别咬
Come on. Come on.
我再也请不动他和我玩了
I couldn't make him play with me.
他只想睡觉
All he wanted to do was sleep.
现在我的自由时间充裕 所以交了个新朋友
I had a lot of free time now, so I made a new friend.
它像只小马
It was like a small horse.
或巨狗
Or a giant dog.
它身上有种独特的气味
With its own special smell
十分美妙又特别恶心
that was so wonderful and disgusting.
真希望我能进去打滚
Oh, I wished I could roll in it.
我们玩得超开心
Oh, we had fun.
直到它不高兴了
Until we didn't.
至少汉娜仍会来玩
At least Hannah still came around.
贝利
Hi, Bailey.
你好
Hi. Hi.
我也想你了
I missed you, too.
好狗狗 好狗狗
Good boy. Good boy.
真是一只好狗狗
Ah, you're such a good boy.
来 来
Come on. Come on!
你 你想去池塘那边吗
You, um... do you want to go to the pond?
我做了些三明治
I made some sandwiches.
好啊
Yeah.
我是说
I mean...
如果你想的话
Yeah, if you want.
我只是 想着如果我们离开屋子
I just... I thought it'd be nice
让你出去转转 挺好的
if we could get out of the house, get you out.
怎么了
What?
汉娜 我知道你是好心
Look, Hannah, it's nice for you to try,
但是你不用 不用这样做
but you don't have to... You don't have to do this.
你不用帮我
You don't have to help me.
我不是为了你
I'm not doing it for you.
是为了我们 我想
I'm doing it for us. I want...
不 你就是为了我才这么做的
No, you're doing this for me.
三周后你就去上大学了
You leave for college in three weeks.
但我随时会回来的
But I'll be back all the time.
对 但我会待在这里
Uh-huh, and I'll be here.
拖着这条废腿
With that.
你不能再自怨自艾了
You have to stop feeling sorry for yourself.
你不能为我这么做 汉娜
You can't do this for me, Hannah.
我愿意为你做任何事
I'd do anything for you.
我不认为我们应该继续在一起了 汉娜
I don't think we should be with each other anymore, Hannah.
我们不该继续在一起了
We shouldn't be with each other anymore.
不会有结果的
It's not gonna work.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
你为什么要这样
Why are you doing this?
贝利
Bailey.
好狗狗
Good boy.
乖
Yeah.
你想玩球吗
You want your ball?
好 给你球
Okay, here's your ball.
去吧
Go on.
再见 贝利
Bye, Bailey.
等等 等等 不要啊
Wait. Wait, no.
别走 留下
No, stay.
我真的很想念汉娜
I really missed Hannah.
伊森也想念他
Ethan missed her, too.
我能感觉到
I could tell.
伊森 我做了三明治
Ethan, I made you a sandwich.
放在后座上 好吗
I'm gonna put it in the backseat, okay?
- 好了 弗兰  - 贝利 贝利 贝利
- All right, Fran.  - Bailey, Bailey, Bailey, Bailey, Bailey.
好狗狗
Good boy.
你会想我的 对吗
You're gonna miss me, huh?
我也会想你的
I'm gonna miss you, too.
别闷闷不乐的 女士们
Don't look so glum, women.
这是所很好的农业学校
It-it's a good agricultural school.
他能学到经营这片农场
He's gonna learn everything he needs to know
所需的各种知识
about running this farm.
对 当然
Yes, absolutely. Yes.
走 过来
All right, go on. Come on.
最好牵住它
Better grab him.
它理解不了的
He's not gonna understand.
来这里
Come here.
- 好狗狗 好狗狗  - 你牵好狗了吗
- Good boy. Good boy.  - Have you got the dog?
我们到这里来
Let's come here.
- 站住 贝利 站住  - 过来 狗狗
- Stay, Bailey, stay.  - Come on, boy.
天气真好 是吧
Great day, huh?
它都长这么大了
He's so grown-up.
它在干吗
What's he doing?
我的天
Oh, my goodness.
好狗狗 贝利
Good boy, Bailey.
帮我保存它 好吗 贝利
You keep that for me, okay, Bailey?
- 接住了  - 是啊
- Caught it.  - Yeah.
再见 伊森
Bye, Ethan.
一路顺风
Drive safe.
拜拜 伊森
See you, Ethan!
不要 贝利
No, Bailey.
- 站住  - 你牵住它 亲爱的
- Stay.  - You got him, honey?
站住 我们玩接球呢
Stay? We're playing fetch.
贝利
Bailey!
我们已经很久没一起玩了
It's been so long since we've played.
贝利
Bailey.
我喜欢这个新版本的接球游戏
I like this new version of fetch.
你是不是疯了 狗老大
You're crazy, you know that, boss dog?
只是下次能不能…别开这么远
Maybe not... Drive so far next time.
帮我照看好这里的一切 好吗
Take care of things around here for me, okay, boy?
我很快就回来
I'll be back soon.
答应我
Promise.
好了 去吧 回家
Come on. Go on. Go home.
人类很复杂
Humans are complicated.
他们总做些狗狗不懂的事情
They do things dogs can't understand.
比如离别
Like leave.
伊森和我注定要在一起
Ethan and I were meant to be together.
但如果伊森不在了
But if there was no Ethan,
我活着还有什么意义
what was the point of my being here?
也许意义就在于不要寻找意义
Maybe the point was not to look for a point.
好了 等一下
Okay, hold on. Hold on.
我很快回来 贝利
I'll be right back, Bailey.
现在 一切都以缓慢的步调流逝
Everything moved at a slower pace now.
没关系
Which was okay,
反正我也不想再跑了
because I never felt like running anymore.
我经常觉得累
I was tired all the time.
不再想着玩儿
I didn't feel like playing anymore.
哪怕是跟小马狗
Not even with horse-dog.
贝利
Hey, Bailey.
你还好吗 孩子
Are you okay, boy?
比尔
Bill?
- 小心点 当心…  - 好的
- Careful. Keep a...  - Okay.
它怎么了
Okay, let's see what we have here.
它的眼睛看起来不大对劲
His eyes just didn't look right.
有…有很多眼屎
They just, uh... they were... They were kind of rheumy.
而且它…老是喘气
And he... and he was panting, he was, uh...
呼吸很沉重
His breathing was labored.
它身上还起了个小肿块
He's-he's also got this little lump in his, uh...
对 它有没有
Oh, yeah. Has he been drinking
- 大量喝水和尿尿  - 没有
- a lot of water and peeing?  - No.
昏昏欲睡 它…不太想出去散步了
Lethargic, so he... he doesn't want to go for walks anymore?
我都不得不把它抱进车里
I had to carry him into the car.
医生 你觉得 我们能为它做点什么
What can we do for him, doctor? What do you think?
我们…我们可以做个检查
Well, we-we... We could do testing,
但恐怕还是一样的结果
but I'm afraid that it would probably be the same results.
它的…它的肾功能在衰退
His... his kidneys are shutting down.
我们能不能…
Can we just...
大家都很难过
Everyone was so sad,
但是我已经没力气去逗他们开心了
but I was too tired to cheer them up.
乔伊斯医生 我能不能借用下你电话
Dr. Joyce, can I, uh... Can I use your phone?
当然可以
Yes. Oh, absolutely.
医生 医生 如果这是个人
Doctor, doctor, uh, if this was a person,
如果它是个人 你是兽医
if this was a person... you're the veterinarian...
如果它是个人 是不是意味着…
if this was a person, would you say that...
你好
Uh, hello.
我想找伊森
Yeah, uh, I'm looking for Ethan.
我是他外公 比尔
It's his grandpa, Bill.
伊森 我是外公
Ethan, it's grandpa.
伊森
Ethan.
你来了吗
Are you here?
我闻不到你
I can't smell you.
你在哪儿
Where are you?
贝利
Hey, Bailey.
他来了
There he was.
我知道他很难过
I could tell he was still sad.
我不想让他难过
I didn't want him to be sad.
小笨狗
Doodle dog.
狗老大
Boss dog, huh?
我知道我来到这世上是为了爱伊森
I knew I was here to love Ethan
让他快乐
and make him happy.
贝利 贝利 贝利 贝利
Oh, Bailey, Bailey, Bailey, Bailey.
我不想就这样离开他
I didn't want to leave him like this.
乖孩子
Good boy.
乖孩子 贝利
Good boy, Bailey.
别担心
Don't worry.
他只会感觉到脖子上一丁点…小刺痛
He'll just feel a little... A little prick in his neck,
然后就可以安息了
and then the pain will go away.
一切又重新开始了
And then it happened again.
妈妈 乳汁
The mother, the milk,
舌头 温暖
the tongue, the warmth.
我回来了
I was back.
但为什么
But why?
伊森去哪儿了
Where was Ethan?
有些东西也不见了
Other things were missing, too.
我怎么没有…
I didn't have a...
什么 我是个女孩
What? I'm a girl?
过来 过来
Come on, come on!
乖孩子 乖孩子
Good girl, good girl.
我的主人很严肃
My man was very serious.
注意
Look.
- 过 过  - 我们工作很辛苦
- Over. Over. Good girl!  - We worked hard.
就算是玩 也被他搞得像在工作
Even when we played, he made it feel like work.
放松 下 下
Easy. Down, down.
找到沃利 搜寻开始
Find Wally. Search! Go!
沃利真是让人头疼
Wally was a disaster,
老在掉东西
always losing pieces of clothing.
你找到他了
You found him.
真棒
Good job. Okay.
[埃莉]
[芝加哥警犬]
难道这就是我的使命
So this is my purpose?
跟玩乐无关
It's not about fun.
- 跟伊森无关  - 来 乖孩子
- It's not about Ethan.  - Come on. Good girl.
我的工作就是搜寻 查找
My job is to seek, find
和展示
and show.
真棒 乖孩子
Good job. Good job.
但即使我做得很棒
But even when I did a good job,
我的主人也还是不开心
my man was still sad.
他很孤单
He was lonely.
我知道曾经有人也住在这里
I could smell someone else used to live here,
但他们的气味很微弱
but their scent was faint.
他们已经很久没出现在这屋子里了
They hadn't been around in a long time.
这时我开始意识到
That's when I realized
世上最糟糕的事 莫过于孤单
being alone might be the worst thing that could happen to you.
我知道想念一个人是什么感觉
I knew how it felt to miss someone.
他也在想念某个人吗
Did he miss someone, too?
不可以
Stop that.
怎么了
What?
睡你自己的床 快去
Dog bed-- now.
埃莉…
Ellie...
睡自己的床 去
Dog bed-- now.
为什么我要听他的
Why did I listen to him?
我不想走
I didn't want to go.
而且我知道 他也不希望我走
And I could tell he didn't want me to go, either.
天啊
Oh, gosh.
能不能让我省点心
Would you give me a break?
不许发牢骚
No whining.
这是枪
Gun.
枪闻起来有股刺鼻的味道
Gun had a smell that stung my nose.
乖乖的
Steady.
坐好
Stay.
放松
Relax.
习惯了就好了
Get used to it.
要坚强
Stay strong.
乖狗狗
Good girl.
怎么了
Yes?
什么
What?
那个我也会
I could do that, too.
我找不到拒绝的理由
You know, I don't see why not.
上来 上来
Come on. Come on.
这是她昨天穿的毛衣
That's the sweater that she was wearing yesterday.
- 好的 女士  - 她今天穿了
- Okay, ma'am.  - Today, she had on
蓝色牛仔裤和蓝色外套
blue jeans and a blue jacket.
你记得是什么时候…
Do you remember what time it was...
我们接到了这里佣人的报案
We got called here on a domestic.
在我们到这之前 是一起绑架案
By the time we got here, it was kidnapping.
前男友 携带武器
Ex-boyfriend, armed.
绑架了十二岁的女孩
Took the 12-year-old girl.
这是什么
What is this?
这是她在被绑架前一天穿过的衣服
This is the last item of clothing she was wearing.
知道了
Okay.
走吧 我们走
Come on. Come on.
一位目击者打电话称
Got a partial plate called in
有一辆蓝色丰田正向东开向水库
on a blue Toyota heading east toward the reservoir.
收到 我们马上过去
Copy that. We're on our way.
埃莉 埃莉
Ellie. Ellie.
快找
Find.
快找 埃莉
Find, Ellie.
真乖 好好找
Good girl. Good find.
椒盐卷饼 披萨 热狗
Pretzel. Pizza. Hot dog.
橡胶 列车 出租车
Rubber. Train. Cab.
咖啡 毛衣 女孩 穿毛衣的女孩
Coffee. Sweater. Girl? Sweater girl!
女孩 女孩
Girl! Girl!
快
Come on.
快点 快
Come on. Come on.
就是那个女孩
That a girl.
追上他 追上他
Get him! Get him!
站住
Halt!
警察
Police!
站住
Halt!
追上他 抓住他
Get him, girl. Get him!
追上他 埃莉
Get him, Ellie!
我说 站住
I said halt!
慢慢地
Slowly!
放开她
Let her go!
别动 站住
Hold it! Hold it!
停下
Stop!
站住
Hey!
Halt!
- 这里  - 在这 她在这
- Hey!  - Hey, hey, there she is.
- 在这里 这里  - 我们来了 有我们呢
- Hey, hey.  - We've got you. We've got you.
- 真棒 干得漂亮  - 走吧
- Good girl. Good girl.  - There you go.
松开
Release!
好了 我们抓住他了 抓住他了
All right, we got him. We got him.
- 起来  - 走
- Get up.  - Let's go.
快 起来
Come on, get up!
快点
Come on.
这里是警犬K27
This is canine unit k-27.
我需要立刻…
I'm gonna need immediate...
支援
assistance.
我的狗中枪了
My dog's been shot.
重复 警犬中枪
I repeat, canine shot.
我一直讨厌中枪
I always hated getting shots.
这绝对是我受过的最重的枪伤
This was definitely the worst shot I ever got.
埃莉
Ellie.
你会没事的
You're gonna be okay.
你是条很棒的狗
You're a good dog.
从卡洛斯的语气中我能听出
I could tell from Carlos's voice
我干得不错
I'd done a good job.
你是条很棒的狗
You're a good dog.
我需要休息一下
I need to rest.
我能就在你的床上睡觉吗
Can I just sleep in your bed?
那是一种不同的生活
That was a different life.
没什么乐趣可言 真的
Not so much fun, really.
但是我做得不错
But I did good work.
开始了
Here we go.
现在我很小并且注意力集中
Now I'm tiny and all ears.
你好啊 小可爱
Hi, you.
你是这世界上最可爱的小狗狗吗
Are you the cutest little puppy in the world?
她闻起来真香
She smelled good,
像阳光和椒盐卷饼的味道
like sunshine and pretzels.
我觉得你是
I think you are.
是吗 你想和我一起回家 对吗
Oh, yeah. You want to come home with me, huh?
好了 你得和我一起回家
Okay, you gotta come home with me.
你和我一起回家 好吗
You gotta come home with me, huh?
你想帮我吗
Are you gonna help me with this?
怎么了
What's happening?
你要去哪 过来
Where are you going? Come here.
怎么了
What's going on?
What's going on, huh?
我看得出来她很伤心
I could tell she was sad.
我得哄她开心
I needed to cheer her up.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
我的尾巴呢
Where's my tail?
咦 我的尾巴去哪了
Hello? Where's my tail?
好了 狗狗 好了
Okay, boy. All right.
快 快 咱们走
Come on. Come on, let's go.
玛雅去哪都带着我
Everywhere she went, Maya brought me along.
真是太棒了
Which was great.
根据美国哲学家
According to the American philosopher
查尔斯·桑德斯·皮尔士
Charles Sanders Peirce,
人类只用符号思考
human beings think only in signs.
她总是给我带吃的
She always brought me something to eat.
我都快忘了饿肚子的感觉了
I almost forgot what it was like to be hungry.
几乎
Well, almost.
- 你好  - 你好
- Hey. Hi.  - Hi.
- 好可爱的狗  - 谢谢
- Cute dog.  - Uh-huh. Thanks.
我们中的几个
Um, listen, uh, a few of us
准备组成一个学习小组
are putting together a study group.
我们准备在伍德福德自习室一起讨论学习
We're meeting at the Woodford common room.
我们希望你能加入
We'd love for you to join us.
我很想去 但是我已经有安排了 所以…
Um, I would, but I have plans, so...
但是我还没说我们什么时候讨论学习
Oh... oh, but I didn't say when we was meeting.
不
No.
不 我只是… 我很忙 我…
No, I just... I'm busy. I...
我知道我会很忙…
Like, I know I'm gonna be busy and, like...
我还得照顾我的狗 所以我…
I got my dog, so I gotta...
谢谢你 我得走了
Thank you. I gotta go.
我很抱歉 我得去遛狗了 所以…
I'm sorry. I have to take my dog out, so...
- 好吧  - 但还是谢谢你
- Okay.  - But thank you.
好吧
Okay.
- 也许下次有机会再约  - 好
- Maybe next time.  - Uh, yeah.
我不知道我是怎么了 蒂诺
I don't know what's wrong with me, Tino.
或许多认识些人挺好的 但是…
Like, yeah, maybe it would be nice to meet people, but...
不 我也该一个人学习因为…
No, also I should just study alone 'cause...
慢着点 慢着点
Slow down. Slow down.
我只有小短腿
My legs are barely even legs.
我觉得自己真蠢
Ugh! I feel like such an idiot.
我很快明白了 虽然玛雅总是在说话
I learned quickly that even though Maya talked all the time,
她很像卡洛斯
she was a lot like Carlos.
我们的小团体里没有别人了
There was no one else in our pack.
只有玛雅和我
Just Maya and me.
但我开始懂她了
But I'm starting to get her.
事实上 我能读她的心
Actually, I can read her mind.
你知道我在想什么吗
You know what I'm thinking?
- 薯条  - 薯条
- Chips.  - Chips.
你知道我在想什么吗
You know what I'm thinking?
- 披萨  - 披萨
- Pizza.  - Pizza.
一定要是披萨啊
Please. Pizza.
- 嗨 克里斯  - 嗨
- Hey, Chris.  - Hi.
- 给你 谢谢  - 拜拜
- Here you go.  - Thank you. Bye.
- 你准备好了吗  - 我准备好了
- You ready?  - I am ready.
你知道我在想什么吗
You know what I'm thinking?
冰淇淋
Ice cream.
这可能有些可笑 但有时
It's ridiculous, but sometimes
我真的觉得你知道我在想什么
I actually think you know what I'm thinking.
冰淇淋 冰淇淋 冰淇淋
Ice cream, ice cream, ice cream.
你知道吗 我一个人待的时间太长了
Ugh. Do you know, I'm spending way too much time alone.
你想吃点冰淇淋吗
You want to go get some ice cream?
你懂我
You read my mind.
我觉得可能就这样了 蒂诺
I think this is it, Tino.
我觉得我们只能相依为命了
I think it's just gonna be you and me.
我不知道 这也挺好的 对吗
I-I don't know. It's fine, right?
因为我爱你 你也爱我
Because I love you and you love me, and...
唯一重要的就是爱
Love is all that matters.
从哪儿得到的爱并不重要
It's not like it matters where you get your love.
只要有东西爱你 对吗
As long as something loves you, right?
我能再来点吗
Can I have some more?
你真贴心
Oh, you're so sweet.
你真可爱
You're so cute.
我爱你
Hi. I love you.
你为什么就不能是我男友呢
Why can't you be my boyfriend, huh?
你为什么就不能再给我点冰淇淋呢
Why can't you give me more ice cream?
还剩一针
--Okay, one more to go.
这些穿白大褂的人类
What's with these white-coat people
干吗总是用尖东西扎我
sticking me with sharp things?
你按时喂他吗
Now, do you feed him at regular times?
挺有规律的
Pretty regular.
你都给他吃什么
What do you give him?
吃的
Food.
狗粮 怎么了
Dog food. What?
或许你应该让他多锻炼些
Maybe give him more exercise.
多遛遛
Go on more walks.
没问题
Sure.
扎针 我讨厌扎针
Shots. I hate those shots.
好了 蒂诺
Okay, Tino.
我们来做运动吧
Let's do this, huh?
这是医嘱 过来吧
Doctor's orders. Come here.
好了 捡球去
All right, get the ball.
走了那么久 现在我又得捡球去
A long walk, and now I have to chase a ball?
把球捡回来 快点
Get the ball. Come on.
我为什么被这般惩罚
Why was I being punished like this?
蒂诺 快点 你是只狗
Tino, come on. You're a dog.
追球去 快去追
Get... chase the ball. Chase it.
- 快点 蒂诺  - 幸运儿
- Come on, Tino.  - Lucky.
蒂诺 这真是太丢人了 好吗
Tino, this is embarrassing, okay?
- 快去吧  - 对不起 今天不行
- Just, come on.  - Sorry, not today.
- 捡球去  - 我没那心情
- Get the ball.  - I'm not in the mood.
之后我看见了她
And then I saw her.
一切都变了
And everything changed.
我的心激动起来
My heart was aflutter.
抓得真棒
What a catch.
蒂诺 把它带回给我
Tino, bring it back to me.
你也与我感同身受吗
Are you feeling what I'm feeling?
对不起
Hey, I'm sorry.
我的狗今天怪怪的
My dog's acting so weird today.
- 不 没事的  - 我们走吧
- No, it's okay.  - Come on, boy. Let's go.
快点 你想追这个吗
Come on, are you gonna chase this?
- 等一下  - 你好
- Wait a minute.  - Oh. Hey.
你和我都上肯特教授的课
You and I both have, uh, Professor Kenter.
是啊
Right. Yeah.
我叫艾尔
I'm-I'm Al.
好的 我叫玛雅
Oh. Okay, I'm Maya.
- 很高兴认识你  - 我很抱歉
- Nice to meet you.  - I'm sorry...
玛雅在说着话 但我不在听
Maya was talking, but I didn't listen.
我脑子里都是她
All I could think of was her.
没事的 我理解的
It's cool. I... No, I, understand.
它一遇到你的狗就像疯了似的
So he's, like, acting crazy around your dog.
干吗不肯呢
Why fight it?
我们闻起来好配
We smell great together.
我们开始天天都能见到罗西
We started seeing Roxy all the time.
不知为什么 艾尔也总是会来
For some reason, Al always came, too.
没过多久
It wasn't long before...
我们就睡在一起了
We slept together.
我真的开始懂了
I'm really starting to get it now.
如果活着有意义 罗西就是那个意义
If there's a point, Roxy is the point.
慢着 出什么事了
Wait. What's going on?
玛雅
Um, Maya?
我心里有些话
There's been something on my mind
一直想告诉你
that I've been wanting to talk to you about.
我记得那个汗湿的气味
Oh, I recognize that sweaty smell.
我们已经在一起一段时间了
We've been together for a while now.
玛雅 我想让你成为我的妻子
--Maya, I want you to be my wife.
- 艾尔 我的天哪  - 事情不太对劲
- Al! Oh, my god!  - Something's wrong here.
- 我愿意  - 玛雅有危险
- Yes!  - Maya's in trouble.
我愿意 过来
Yes! Yay! Come here!
- 亲爱的 我愿意  - 太棒了
- Oh, honey, yes!  - Yeah.
这儿有危险 躲到我身后 罗西
There is danger. Get behind me, Roxy.
我会保护大家的
I'll protect us all!
艾尔
Al!
我牵住蒂诺了
Okay. I got Tino. I got Tino. I got Tino.
等一下等一下
Okay, wait, wait. Hold on!
不 罗西 别这样
No, Roxy. Stop it!
妈妈 拿一下这些花
Okay. Mom, hold the... Hold these.
好了 过来吧
Okay, come here. Come on.
- 我觉得我们准备好了  - 我们开始吧
- I think we're ready.  - Okay, let's do this.
完美
Okay, perfect.
准备好
Ready.
你很嫉妒因为法伦有了孩子
You're jealous because Fallon's had her baby,
这使得你更偏执多疑了
and that's made you even more paranoid.
亚历克西斯会被揍的
Alexis gonna get her butt whupped
- 要是她还这么口无遮拦  - 是吧
- she keep running off the mouth like that.  - Right?
因为克里斯塔尔再也受不了这事了
'Cause Krystle's not gonna take much more of this.
- 我没有  - 这太疯狂了
- I haven't.  - This is crazy.
我给你说了吧 我给你说了吧
I told you. I told you.
我的天啊
Oh, my gosh.
- 什么  - 打她 克里斯塔尔
- What?  - Oh, get her, Krystle.
我的天啊
Oh, my gosh.
她的肚子里是什么声音
What's all that noise in her stomach?
是她吃的东西的声音吗
Was it something she ate?
她们要杀了对方啊
Yo, they're trying to kill each other.
什么
What?
不
Oh, no.
- 这是一个宝宝  - 她在呼吸吗
- It was a baby.  - Is she breathing?
你要放松点 亲爱的
You gotta relax, honey.
她在呼吸呢 好吧
She's breathing, okay?
也许我们应该叫醒她来确认一下
Uh, maybe we should wake her up just to be sure.
我不明白为什么他们要生个宝宝
I didn't understand why they got a baby.
这把他们的注意力都转移走了
It took all their attention.
幸好罗西和我有所需的一切
Good thing roxy and I already had everything we needed.
我们彼此
Each other.
小宝宝
Hey, baby.
后来他们生了更多的宝宝
Then they went and got more babies.
看上去像是我的错
Seemed like a mistake to me.
不久 我必须过着逃跑的生活了
Soon, I had to live my life on the run.
找到他了
Found him!
无处可逃
There was no escape.
我允许他们对我为所欲为
I let them do what they wanted to me.
我愿意做任何事情以便罗西可以安全
I'd do anything so that roxy could be safe.
那是我的使命 随时保护她
That was my mission: To protect her at all times.
我想 说实话
I guess, if I was really honest,
我喜欢得到所有的关注
I liked all the attention.
随着罗西和我渐渐变老
As roxy and I got older,
我们的关系更加稳固了
our connection grew stronger.
她也一直如我们初见时
And she never lost the spark
耀眼迷人
that drew me to her in the first place.
有一天 罗西去看兽医了
One day, roxy went to the vet.
她就再也没有回来过
And she never came back.
看我 看我
Look at me! Look at me!
每个人对我都很好
Everyone was good to me.
但随着岁月的流逝 我很想念罗西
But as the years went by, I missed Roxy.
没有她一切都不一样了
It just wasn't the same without her.
蒂诺
Hey, tino.
Hey, Tino.
你知道我在想什么吗
You know what I'm thinking?
是的
Yes.
我知道你在想什么
I know what you're thinking.
披萨
Pizza.
不是吗
No?
不是披萨吗
No pizza?
我不饿
I'm not hungry.
好吧
Okay.
蒂诺…
Tino...
你在想什么呢
What are you thinking?
蒂诺 你在想什么呢
Tino, what are you thinking?
我在想我准备好了
I'm thinking I'm ready.
这真的是我最美好的生活之一
One of my best lives, really.
我回来了
I'm back.
又一次
Again.
但是为什么呢
But why?
- 小狗想要只小狗吗  - 你好啊 小朋友
- Puppies! Want a puppy?  - Hey there, little fella.
- 卖小狗了  - 想买一只吗
- Puppies for sale!  - Want to buy one?
有想买小狗的吗
Who wants a puppy?
你好啊
Hi!
我们又开始新生活了
Here we go again.
看看我抱的是什么
Look what I got. Huh?
我看到了
Yeah, I am looking.
看他多可爱啊
Look how cute he is.
你太不理智了
You know, it's-it's crazy.
谁来照顾他
Who's gonna take care of him?
我会的
I will.
好了 我给他取名华夫饼
Come on. I named him waffles.
不准进屋
Not inside.
吃吧
Come on.
我一直告诉她你会越长越大
I kept telling her you were going to get bigger.
所以她现在不太喜欢你了 对吧
Not so into you now, is she?
我哪里都没有去过
I never went anywhere.
我从未玩耍过
I never played.
感觉就像没有我日子也会一天天过去
It was like the days went on and on without me.
你有三十天的时间来处理掉这个
You have 30 days to deal with this.
当警察来的时候
When the officer came,
我以为又是要领我去参加找东西表演
I thought it was to take me to do find-and-show.
但她自己走了
But she left without me.
他很脏 我们要把他赶走
He's dirty. We're getting rid of him.
我们不能把狗赶走
We are not going to get rid of that dog.
够了 我们要把他赶走
That's enough! We're getting rid of him.
我把他带回来的 我们要照顾好他
I took him in here, and we're gonna take care of him.
你保证可以给他找个好家庭 是吗
You'll make sure he finds a nice home, right?
一个负责任的人
Somebody responsible?
是的
Yeah.
快来 出来
Come on. Out.
动起来
Move it.
我们走 快来
Let's go. Come on.
动起来
Move.
再见 小狗
So long, doggie.
现在我应该走回家吗
Now I'm supposed to walk home?
这似乎太不公平了
That didn't seem very fair.
但当我好好考虑后
But when I thought about it,
我不想回到那个家了
I didn't want to go back to that home.
快来 来这里
Come on. Over here.
看 妈妈
Look, mom.
看起来很有趣
That looks like fun.
坐 坐 你喜欢那个吗
Sit. Sit. You like that?
已经很久没有开心玩耍了
It's been so long since I've had fun.
她要去哪里
Where is she going?
我认识你吗
Do I know you?
你身上有些东西
There's something about you.
是…你的味道
It's... your smell.
你有点脏脏的
You're a scruffy one.
你迷路了吗
Are you lost?
你从哪里来的
Where are you from?
你有颈圈吗
You got a collar?
我知道那个味道
I know that smell.
别害怕
Don't be afraid.
那是…在很久以前
It's... from a long time ago.
我之前来过这里吗
Had I been here before?
真开心我能离开城市
I was so happy to leave the town behind.
我鼻子充满了清新的味道
My nose was full of fresh new smells.
这里有个味道你永不会忘记
And then there are the smells you never forget.
火车 苔藓
Train. Moss.
树木 马 垃圾
Trees. Horse. Garbage.
是小马狗
It was horse-dog!
会是一样的吗
Could it be the same?
是一样的耶
Ah, it was the same.
那是不是意味着伊森也曾在这
Could it mean Ethan was here, too?
那应该够我们撑到月底
That ought to cover us to the end of the month.
伊森
Ethan?
不可能是他
That can't be him.
告诉弗雷德我会去镇里
Tell Fred that I will be in town...
是他吗
Is that him?
明日去结账好吗
...tomorrow to settle up, okay?
会跟他说的
Will do.
是他
It is him!
是他 太棒了
It's him! Yes!
太棒了 是他
Yes, it's him!
是我啊
It's me!
狗老大 贝利贝利贝利
Boss dog! Bailey, Bailey, Bailey
你的傻狗狗
doodle dog!
你从哪来的
Where'd you come from?
经过了这么世 我真的找到你了
After all these lives, I'd actually found him.
我找到了伊森
I found Ethan.
我敢打赌你饿了
I'm gonna make a bet you're hungry.
吃吧
Here you go.
看来是真饿坏了
You must be.
没有人喜欢我煮的东西
Nobody likes my cooking.
不要这样看着我
Don't look at me like that.
你不能留在这
You can't stay here.
你得回家去
You gotta go home.
你有主人
You belong to somebody.
家 对啊
Home. Yes.
对 我回家了
Yes, I'm home.
回家吧 狗狗
Go home, dog.
回家吧
Go home.
你是一条固执的狗狗 是吗
You're a stubborn one, aren't you?
然后 周二晚间
Then, Tuesday night,
降雨量为七十六毫米
we got three tenths of an inch of rain.
确保它能找个好家
Be sure he gets a good home.
它是一条好狗
He's a good dog.
当然
Sure.
不不不 不要把我留在这
No. No, don't leave me here.
这里是收容站
This is a white-coat place.
我是你的
I belong with you.
再见 狗狗
So long, dog.
你想要离开这吗
You want to get out of here?
你想走吗
Do you want to go?
来吧 我们走
Come on, let's go.
我又坐回了前排
I was back in the front seat.
小家伙
Okay, buddy.
看来我们俩要相依为命了
Guess it's gonna be you and me.
还有那头驴
And the donkey.
驴是什么
What's a donkey?
你上一次洗澡是什么时候
Now, when was the last time you got a bath?
真是条乖狗
That's a good boy.
洗好了
There you go. All right.
爬出去 我们走
Just step out. Out. Let's go!
干的好
There you go.
[巴蒂]
你会得到一个新的项圈
You're getting a new collar.
看起来它可没有少吃
Doesn't look like he's missed too many meals.
- 它体型很好  - 嗯 是条好狗
- He's in good shape.  - Yeah, he's a good boy.
是不是啊
Aren't you, huh?
但伊森似乎还是很伤心
But Ethan still seemed sad.
也许是因为他一个人睡
Maybe it was because he slept alone.
我想要帮他 可我不知道如何帮
I wanted to help him, but I didn't know how.
等等 等等
Wait. Wait.
等一下
Hold that thought.
贝利 就这么办
Okay, Bailey, let's do this.
快点
Hurry.
快快快快快
Hurry, hurry, hurry, hurry.
就是这儿了
This is the place.
我在找…
I'm looking for...
快 卡莉 到这来 宝贝
Come on, Carly. Come here, girl.
- 过来 卡莉  - 过来吧 卡莉
- Come on, Carly.  - Come on, Carly.
快来 卡莉
Come here, Carly.
能帮我开下门吗
Can you get the gate for me?
- 好的 妈妈  - 谢谢
- Yes, mommy.  - Thank you.
乖狗狗
Good girl.
抱歉
Oh, sorry.
瑞秋
Rach.
快看 威尔
Oh, hey. Look, Will.
- 外婆来了  - 外婆
- Grandma's here.  - Hi, grandma.
那又有那种气味了
There's that smell again.
- 最近感觉怎么样  - 挺好的
- How are you feeling?  - I'm pretty good.
真是个惊喜
This is a surprise.
现在更浓了
It's stronger now.
我觉得我该给你们准备些吃的了
I thought I'd bring you some groceries.
- 是汉娜  - 谢谢
- It's Hannah!  - Aw. Hmm, thanks.
你还在这
You're still here?
虽然你看起来不一样了
Oh, you look different.
但闻起来还像饼干一样
But you still smell like biscuits.
这是谁的狗
Who is this?
公园里的流浪狗
It's the, uh, stray from the park.
流浪狗 真的吗
A stray? Really?
你好哇
Well, hello there.
多好一条狗啊
What a good dog.
它肯定不是流浪狗
Well, he's certainly not a stray,
因为它有项圈
'cause he's got a collar.
让我看看
Let's see.
它的名字是巴蒂
His name is Buddy.
看看 它的主人是
Let's see. He belongs to...
[伊森·蒙哥马利]
出来啊 伊森
Come on, Ethan.
我能闻出来你在里面
I can smell you in there.
我不想把你留在这
I don't want to leave you here.
但我想他应该不在家
But I guess he's not home.
嗨 伊森
Hi, Ethan.
嗨 汉娜
Hi, Hannah.
我把你的狗带回来了
I brought your dog home.
你一定过的很辛苦吧
Must have been tough on you,
多年前就失去了丈夫
losing your husband after all those years.
嗯 所以我格外想念我的女儿
Yeah, it made me miss my daughter a lot.
然后 随着孙子的出生
And then, with the new baby coming,
我觉得瑞秋和米格尔真的很需要帮手
I thought Rachel and Miguel could really use the help.
嗯
Yeah.
你要在这待多久啊
How long you get to stay for?
我不是来探亲的 伊森
Uh, well, I'm... I'm not visiting, Ethan.
大概一个月前我就搬回来住了
I moved back about a month ago.
你搬了吗
Y-you did?
欢迎回家
Welcome home.
谢谢
Thanks.
这个地方还跟以前一样
Well, this place is still the same.
对啊
Yeah.
加油啊
Oh, come on.
那你呢
So, what about you?
你 你就再没遇上某个人或
You... you never met anyone or...
找不到对的人
Never found the right fit.
我真的很固执
I'm really stubborn.
这点我知道
I know that.
当你把心思投入到一件事中 就是那样
When you put your mind to something, that was that.
是的
Yeah.
这样有助于把事情搞定
That's good for getting things done.
但是不利于发展感情
It's not so good for relationships.
好吧
Okay, well...
好吧 就这样
Okay, here we go.
它们会互相舔脸
They're gonna lick faces.
这样非常好
Well, look, this was really nice.
我得走了
I gotta go.
谢谢你 伊森
Thank you, Ethan.
等一下 什么
Wait, what?
拜托
Oh, come on!
谢谢你把我的狗带回来
Hey, thanks for bringing back my dog.
不客气 再见
You're welcome. Bye.
汉娜
Hey, Hannah.
我…
I, uh...
我欠你一句道歉
I owe you an apology.
为我们之间发生的事情道歉
For what happened to us.
以前的事
Back then.
别担心
Well, don't worry.
那是很久很久以前了
It was a long, long time ago.
不
No.
我把你推开了
I pushed you away.
而且我那时对这个世界真的很愤怒
And I was... I was really mad at the world.
我只是想让你知道
And I just want you to know that not a day goes by
我每一天都在为那样做后悔
that I don't kick myself for doing that.
这就是那种流汗的味道
There's that sweaty smell.
你觉得
You think, uh,
如果我们一起做点什么
it'd be crazy if...
是件疯狂的事吗
we did something together?
你是想跟我约会吗
Are you asking me out on a date?
我只是觉得如果我就看着你开车走了
Well, I just think that I'd be an all-time fool
那我就是个大大的白痴
if I just watched you drive away.
别说话了 快用鼻子吧
Enough talking. Use your nose.
不要
Then don't.
好的 现在你们做对了
Okay, now you're getting it.
好的 太棒了
Yes! Yes!
离这儿远点
Get out of here.
给他们点空间
Give 'em some space.
那边有一点 这就是为什么…
Few right there, that's why...
你好啊 小可爱
Hi, you little cutie pie.
我的水里有薄荷
Ew. My water has mint in it.
你开心吗
You have a good time?
它们一旦开始互相舔脸
Once they started licking faces,
就没人能阻止了
no one could stop them.
伊森终于得到他需要的了
Ethan finally had what he needed.
他很开心
He was happy.
我也很开心
I was happy, too.
不好意思 大家
Excuse me, everybody.
我想感谢你们今天能够来到这里
I-I would like to thank you all for coming here today.
- 这对汉娜和我很重要  - 干杯
- It means a lot to Hannah and I.  - Cheers.
我一直想要有个大家庭
I've always wanted a big family.
在一天之内 我就拥有了一个
All in one day, I've got one.
你没说它有多大
You didn't tell me how big it was.
我只想说说我有多感恩
I just would like to say how grateful I am
我美丽的女孩
that my beautiful girl
重新回到了我的生命中
walked back into my life.
谢谢你
Thank you.
生命就是个谜
Life's a mystery.
干杯
Cheers.
我还想要做一件事
There was one thing I still wanted.
我想要他知道那是我
I wanted him to know it was me.
我们昨晚非常开心
We had so much fun last night.
我就是贝利
That I was Bailey.
昨晚真的很棒
What a great night.
别说了
Stop.
你很棒
You were amazing.
是的 你也很棒
Yeah. You, too.
- 等等 贝利以前不就是这样吗  - 是啊
- Wait, didn't Bailey used to do that?  - Yeah.
狗狗都会这样做
It's a dog thing.
贝利 我是贝利
Bailey. I'm Bailey.
肯定有办法的
There's gotta be a way.
等等
Hmm. Wait.
这味道有点熟悉
That's familiar.
我闻到了…我的味道
I smelled... me.
你叼着什么呢
What do you got there?
你在哪发现的
Where did you find that?
你想玩吗
You want to play?
准备好
Get ready.
你得追着这个
You have to really go after this one.
去追吧
Go get it.
好样的
Good boy!
来 把它带回来
Come on, bring it here.
不错
Good one.
好
All right.
你自己去玩 好吗
You go play, all right?
我得回去了
Gotta get back.
怎么了 你想要什么
What? What do you want?
这太疯狂了
This is nuts.
好吧 哥们儿
All right, buddy.
你想来点好玩的
You want to go for the showstopper?
你想试试吗 你想要吧
You want to try it? You want to get it?
准备好了吗
Ready?
我准备好了
I am ready.
好了 去吧
Okay. Go!
你在哪里学的这招 哥们儿
Where did you learn how to do that, buddy?
你有点吓到我的 狗老大
You are really starting to freak me out, boss dog.
没错 伊森 这就对了
Yes, Ethan, that's right.
我是你的狗老大 我是贝利
I'm your boss dog. I'm Bailey.
说出来
Say it.
狗老大
Boss dog?
你是狗老大
Are you the boss dog?
不会吧
No.
是的 是我 伊森
Yes. It's me, Ethan.
是我
It's me.
贝利
Bailey?
Bailey.
狗老大
Boss dog.
贝利 贝利 贝利 贝利 贝利
Bailey, Bailey, Bailey, Bailey, Bailey.
太好了
Mmm, yeah.
所以 在我的狗生里
So, in all my lives as a dog,
这是我学到的东西
here's what I've learned.
很显然 要玩得开心
Have fun, obviously.
无论何时
Whenever possible,
找到一些需要拯救的人 并拯救他们
find someone to save, and save them.
去舔那些你所爱的人
Lick the ones you love.
不为已经发生的事而悲伤
Don't get all sad-faced about what happened
也不为没发生的事而苦恼
and scrunchy-faced about what could.
- 活在当下就好  - 去吧
- Just be here now.  - Go!
好 去追吧
Okay, go get it.
- 活在当下  - 就这样
- Be here now.  - That's it.
这就是一条狗的使命
That's a dog's purpose.